# **David Honea**

## **Production Foreman - Joseph Oat Corporation**

Fairless Hills, PA - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/David-Honea/2721f69efb63a069

Vast experience as a Manufacturing Engineer/Plant Foreman in the development of the new advanced Nuclear, Chemical and Naval products. CNC programming, Tool and Fixture Design, Routing of all manufacturing operations, Time standards and estimating cost for new machined and fabricated parts (including material and tooling cost), Plate layout and nesting sheets for material planning and ordering, Specify and control all machines and tools required for production. Vendor and Customer liaison is the main area of expertise.

#### **TECHNOLOGY**

- Certificate of Computer Aided Design (CAD)
- Certificate of Computer-Aided Machining (CAM)/Manufacturing Processes
- · CNC machine installation and coding
- · Windows, Word, Excel and Project computer skills
- Senior member of the Society of Manufacturing Engineers and member of the Machine Tool Association since 1995
- ASME and Military specifications
- · OSHA standards for Plant safety

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## **Production Foreman**

Joseph Oat Corporation - Camden, NJ - 2012 to Present

- Run the daily operations of the plant
- Supervise the fabrication, welding, testing and machining operations
- Work closely with Quality Control Department and Customer Inspectors
- In charge of building large Nuclear and Chemical Pressure Vessels
- · Implementing cost saving methods to operations
- Scheduling operational cost and time lines
- · In charge of plant safety and maintenance

•

#### **Senior Manufacturing Engineer**

D.C. Fabricators Inc - Florence, NJ - 1995 to 2011

- Establishment of the manufacturing operations for all products produced
- To manage the individual project budget and it's timing
- For all US businesses, development and management of the quoting system
- To approve all the specifications of the products and the processes for operation
- To program CNC Machines as required. (Including Plate Cutting and Gun Drilling)
- To specify all machining operations and tools required
- Responsibility to design special tools and fixtures for machining and fabricating for all manufacturing functions
- Identification and development of vendor base for the tooling functions
- Materials planning, layout and cost functions

## **Manufacturing Engineer**

Alfa-Laval Separation, Inc - Warminster, PA - 1991 to 1995

- New products launching
- · Management of the budget of the project and its timing
- To calculate the cost of production in order to determine the pricing strategy
- Programmed CNC machines (Including 7 Axis Mill/Turn machine)
- Tool and Fixture design and CAD drawings requirements

### **Industrial Engineer / Methods Engineer**

Heintz Aero Space, Inc - Philadelphia, PA - 1988 to 1991

To undertake the responsibility to lead the projects of advanced process technology

- To design the manufacturing process and accordingly co-ordinate with equipment and tooling resources for the machining of USAF jet engine components
- Capacity analysis
- · Special Tooling and manufacturing CAD drawings

## **Industrial Engineer**

United Aero Products, Inc - Burlington, NJ - 1984 to 1988

- Management of tooling and capital budget
- Capacity analysis and time study of operations
- To design the manufacturing processes for USAF jet engine components
- Negotiation of the contracts with the suppliers for equipment and tooling
- Proper co-ordination of the capital and acquisition of tooling equipment, its analysis and strategy

## **Manufacturing Engineer**

Franklin Electric, Inc - Fallsington, PA - 1979 to 1984

- To use the standardization techniques
- Program CNC and NC Machines
- Process sheet metal punching and forming operations
- Maintain Tool requirements for all operations

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Associates in Science

Bucks County Community College - Newtown, PA 1974